VINIT KOSHTI

Data Scientist/Machine Learning Engineer



EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder

PeerXP Technologies

Movenber 2017 - September 2019 ♀ Gurugram

- My Startup was basically providing DevOps service(automating complete CI/CD process) for various companies project which were based on different technologies.
- My Contribution: Connecting with client and understanding their project, Developing CI/CD yml script for automating complete DevOps lifecycle using GitLab and other tools.
- My Drive: I was continuously working on Machine Learning and Deep Neural Network and how to bring innovation in our product/services.

10000 Startups

Incubatee at NASSCOM

July 2018 - September 2019

♀ Gurugram

Y Combinator

Graduated from Y Combinator Startup School

August 2018 - November 2018

Online

PROJECTS & SPECIALIZATION

Machine Learning

Applied AI Course by Shrikanth Varma

 QUORA-question similarity, NETFLIX-movie recommender system, AMAZON-fashion discovery engine, STACKOVERFLOW-tag predictor, FACEBOOK-friend recommendation, NYCTAXI-demand prediction, CANCER-diagnosis using medical records, AUTONOMOUS CAR

Deep Learning Nanodegree Udacity

- DOG BREED CLASSIFIER: Designed and trained a convolutional neural network to analyze images of dogs and correctly identify their breeds. Used transfer learning and well-known architectures to improve this model.
- GENERATE TV SCRIPTS: Build a recurrent neural network on TensorFlow to process text. Used it to generate new episodes of your favorite TV show, based on old scripts.
- GENERATE FACES: Build a pair of multi-layer neural networks and make them compete against each other in order to generate new, realistic faces.
- DEPLOYING A SENTIMENT ANALYSIS MODEL: Trained and deployed PyTorch sentiment analysis model.

ABOUT ME

Data Scientist with 2 years of industry and 1 year of Advance Machine Learning experience. I have experience of founding a Tech Startup to publishing research work. I have found that nothing satisfies me more than meeting new people, developing new relationships, solving problems and contributing to the overall growth of a business.

STRENGTHS

Python C++ Javascript MySQL

Machine Learning - SVMs, RF, XGBoost

Deep Learning - Neural Nets, CNN, RNN, GAN

Probability and Statistics

ETL - Expolarotary Data Analysis

Tensorflow-Keras-PyTorch

Big Data - Spark, Hive AWS - MS Azure

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science NIIT University

July 2014 - May 2018

HONOURS & AWARDS

Global Business Idea Hackathon 2017
Won this hackathon conducted by Accel Partners.

Smart India Hackathon 2017
Top 3 National Level Winning Team.

Inspire Award Warrant received from the DEPARTMENT OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY of Government of India.

Member of Advisory Committee elected as a member of the President's student advisory committee at NIIT University.

PUBLICATIONS

Part of the AISC book series (Springer, volume 799)

- Koshti, Vinit et al. (2018). "Online Partitioning of Large Graphs for Improving Scalability in Recommender Systems." In: Springer Nature, Singapore.
- Computational Intelligence: Theories, Applications and Future Directions Volume II
- Abstract: Today social network is changing the way we think and do things. The people we 'trust' or 'are close to' in our social network continuously shape our views about different things. This trust-based relationship can be harnessed to recommend items to users. In this paper, we aim to tackle the problem of scalability in online recommender systems using an online graph partitioning algorithm.

Conference Proceedings - Ready for Submission

- Koshti, Vinit (2019). Algorithm for finding K-shortest path and K-alternate path in graph topology.
- Abstract: In this project we have tried to reduce the runtime of conventional techniques by exploiting the physical structure of the road network and using network pre-processing techniques. Our algorithms may not guarantee optimal results but can offer significant savings in terms of memory requirements and processing speed.

REFEREES

Mr. Balaii S R

@ NIIT Limited

■ balajisr@niit.com

Senior Vice President - Education Technology

Prof. Prosenjit Gupta

- @ NIIT University
- prosenjit.gupta@niituniversity.in, prosenjit_gupta@acm.org

Ph. D., University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, USA

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- A Big Investment Enthusiast and financial advisor.
- InvestorBhai Blog and Community for Investors. WordPress website is completely managed by me.
- Travelling is Life.
- Music does its work.
- Book Reading Investment related and self-help books.